<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Wine and Meet</title>
    <link>https://wineandmeet.net/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Wine and Meet</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://wineandmeet.net/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Wine Tasting at 11ème Domaine</title>
      <link>https://wineandmeet.net/post/11emedomaine_winetasting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wineandmeet.net/post/11emedomaine_winetasting/</guid>
      <description>We enjoyed a great wine tasting at 11ème Domaine. Here are some notes :
Sparkling Wine We began our wine tasting with a sparkling wine from Saumure, it has subtile bubbles with white flower aromas that extend into more generous while balanced taste.
 Domain name: Chateau de Montguéret Region : Saumure, Loire, France Grapes: 60% Chenin Blanc, 20% Chardonnay, 15% Cabernet Franc, 5% Grolleau Gris  White Wines The first white wine was fresh with golden apple, acacia flower and flint aromas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 2 most known Georgian wine grapes</title>
      <link>https://wineandmeet.net/post/georgian_grapes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wineandmeet.net/post/georgian_grapes/</guid>
      <description>Georgia has approximately 530 indigeneous grape wines, which is considerable when you think that worldwide there are around 10 000 ! Georgia alone has 1&amp;frasl;20 of the worldwide wine varieties !
Many of them are grown in &amp;ldquo;wine libraries&amp;rdquo;, but the 2 most commonly used are :
 Saperavi grape has red flesh and red skin! It gives often fully opaque wines with a lot of tannic and rich aromas such as dark berries, licorice, grilled meat, tobacco, chocolate and spices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Qvevri : Georgian traditional wine-making process</title>
      <link>https://wineandmeet.net/post/georgia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wineandmeet.net/post/georgia/</guid>
      <description>During my trip in Georgia, I discovered the Qvevri wine-making process. A Qvevri is a big jar put in the soil where wine is fermented. The process uses grapes, the skins, the stalks and pips which give very remarkable wines. Generally the process goes as follows:
 grapes are pressed in satsnakheli (wine press) Chacha is poured in Qvevri (pomace: grape skins, stalks and pips) after fermentation it is sealed for aging for 6 months roughly  However we can distinguish two different styles:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Domaine des Poncetys</title>
      <link>https://wineandmeet.net/post/selection_poncetys/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wineandmeet.net/post/selection_poncetys/</guid>
      <description>Thanks to domaine des poncetys with this les terres blanches a saint-veran appelation wine from burgundy. Enjoy it&amp;rsquo;s sunny color, aromas of honey, benzine, lemon, minerality. The body is tense due to its acidity and freshness balanced by a residual honey sweetness. At last enjoy the herbal finish. Great with sea food !</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>